Here, the Markov Assumption will help us again.
ここでもう一度マルコフ仮定が役に立ちます
Since you assume you're now this tagged x_t,
これを xt とタグ付けしたと仮定すると
it doesn't really matter what the car observes and how it moves before x_t.
車両が何を観察し それが x_t の前にどう動いたかは問題ではありません
These values were already used to estimate x_t,
これらの値は 既に x_t を推定するために使用されました
and that t will not benefit from these values.
この t はこれらの値から得たベネフィットではありません
This means, we assume that that t is independent
つまり t は前回の観測値またはコントロールすべてから
of all previous observations and the controls.
独立していると考えられます
Again, this is an example of the use of the Markov Assumption.
マルコフ仮定の使用例は次のようになります
And I can simplify our posterior distribution to p of z_t,
事後分布は z_t の p として簡略化し
only depends on x_t and the map.
x_t とマップにのみ依存するようにできます
Let's take a closer look to the observation model.
この観測モデルをより詳しく見てみましょう
Do you remember that that t is or could be a vector of multiple observations?
t は複数の観測値のベクトルであるか その可能性があることを覚えていますか
This means, we rewrite the observation model in this way.
これは 観測モデルをこの方法で書き直すということです
Now we assume that the noise behavior of the individual range values
それぞれの範囲値 z_t_1 から z_t_K のノイズ動作は
z_t_1 to z_t_K is independent.
独立していると仮定します
This also means that all observations are independent.
これは同時に すべての観測値も独立していることを示します
And it allows us to represent a observation model as a product
よって観測モデルは 各単一範囲の測定におけるそれぞれの
of the individual probability distributions of each single range measurement.
確率分布にわたる積として表すことができます
Now the question is,
ここで問題は
how we should define the observation model forcing a range measurement?
範囲の測定を強制する観測モデルをどのように定義するか です
In general, there are a lot of different observation models,
一般に 観測モデルは多様で複数あります
because we have a lot of different sensors like lidars,
ライダー カメラ レーダー 超音波センサーなど
cameras, radars, or ultransonic sensors.
異なるセンサーがあるからです
And each sensor has a specific noise behavior and performance.
それぞれのセンサーには 特定のノイズ動作やパフォーマンスがあります
The observation model also depends on the type of the map.
さらに 観測モデルはマップの種類に依存します
You can have dense 2D or 3D grid maps or sparse feature-based maps.
密集した 2D または 3D のグリッドマップや スパース(疎)な特徴点ベースのマップを使用できます
In our 1D example,
センサーが
we assume that our sensor measures that
運転方向にある最も近いオブジェクト n までの距離を測定する
range to the n closest objects in driving direction.
と仮定した 1 次元の例を考えます
As shown on the right side,
右側に示すとおり
the car measures 90 meters to the first and 37 meters to the second object.
車両は最初のオブジェクトまで 19 m 2 番目のオブジェクトまで 37 m と測定しました
As stated before, the objects represents the landmarks in our map.
前述のとおり オブジェクトはマップ上のランドマークを表します
Here, we assume the observation noise can be modeled
ここで 観測ノイズは 1 m の標準偏差のある
as a Gaussian with a standard deviation of one meter.
ガウス分布としてモデル化されると仮定します
We also assume that our sensor can measure in a range between zero and 100 meters.
また センサーは 0～100 m の範囲を測定可能であるという仮定です
To implement observation model,
観測モデルを実装するには
you use a given x_t and the given map to estimate so called pseudo ranges.
与えられた xt とマップを使用して いわゆる疑似距離を推定します
These pseudo ranges represent a true range values and as assumption,
これらの擬似距離は正しい距離値を表しており、仮定として、
your car would stand at the specific position,
あなたの車は特定の位置 xt、
x_t, and the map.
そして、地図上に表れます
For example, assume your car is standing here at position 20,
たとえば 車が位置 20 にあり
and would observe five meters to the first,
最初のランドマークまで 5 m
11 meters to the second,
2 番目まで 11 m
39 metres to the third,
3 番目まで 39 m
and 57 meters to the last landmark.
最後までは 57 m と観測したと仮定します
Compared to the real observations,
実際の観測と比較すると
this position seems very unlikely, right?
この位置になる可能性はとても低いと思いませんか
So observation would rather fit to a position around 40.
観測から判断するとむしろ 40 あたりの位置に一致しそうです
Based on this example,
この例に基づき
the observation model for a single range measurement is
単一範囲の測定における観測モデルは
defined by the probability of the following normal distribution,
この正規分布の確率によって定義されます
defined by the mean z-star_t_K and our sigma.
正規分布は z-star_t_K とシグマの平均値によって定義されます
These insights allows you to implement observation model in C++.
これらの見識により 観測モデルを C++ で実装することが可能になります
But before you go back to the coding part,
コーディングに戻る前に
I would like to finalize the theory of the base localization further.
ベースローカライゼーション理論をまとめておきましょう